

### **PROFILE**

Experienced Talent Acquisition Manager devising strategy and process to execute recruitment sourcing and recruiting campaigns. Finding and screening candidates and developing corporate policy for talent bench marking, talent assessment and interviewing policies. Develops and leads strategic initiatives to recruit and select high caliber, professional and diverse workforce that identifies with business culture.

### CONTACT

ADDRESS: F-101, Concorde Manhattans, Neeladri Road, Electronic City -Phase 1, Bengaluru 560100

PHONE: +91 9833414332

EMAIL: vpoonam555@gmail.com

### **TOOLS**

- ATS
- LinkedIn, iMocha, MyInterview, Kayako, SmartRecruiters, Slack
- Tools- MS Office, Windows, MS
   Teams, Zoom, Slack, Google Meet
- AV Aids

# POONAM VERMA

**Talent Acquisition Manager** 

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### Talent Acquisition (Freelancer for Leadership and Volume Hiring, both IT and Non-IT)

2022-04 - Current

- To organize and publish adverts on Jobs Portals, external web sites, release IJP's, prepare reports on activity and progress, conducting skills tests
- Prioritizing positions, screening resumes, using Xray method, Boolean search and various other methods, evaluate resumes, interviews and present qualified candidates to hiring managers and solicit feedback to refine recruitment strategy.
- Compensation conversations with hiring managers, salary negotiation.
- Prepare dashboards highlighting open positions and their status, manage candidate database.

## Recruitment and Training Manager (Volume Hiring) WhitehatJr Education Technology Pvt. Ltd.

2020-03 - 2022-03

- Conducted orientation sessions and organized on the job training for new hires.
- Explained HR policies, procedures, laws, standards and regulations to each employee.
- Developed recruiting strategies to identify qualified candidates and build network.
- Evaluated strengths and weaknesses of candidates through effective screening process.
- Prepare offer letters; induction, prepare performance review documentation etc.

# Asst. Professor HR and Placement Manager Welingkar's Institute of Management Studies

2017-06 - 2020-03

- Empowered students through counselling and skill building exercises.
- Planned and promoted career planning presentations, work experience programs and career workshops.

### **SKILLS**

- Excellent Communication Skills
- Using Job Boards, Resume Parsing, Psychometric assessments, gamified assessments.
- Background Screening
- Virtual Onboarding
- Employment Branding
- Workforce segmentation
- Video Interviews
- Human Resource Operations, Policies and Practices.
- Customer Service
- Training and Facilitation
- Languages known English, Hindi, Marathi

- Collaborated with teachers and administrators in development, evaluation and revision of school programs and in preparation of master schedules for curriculum offerings.
- Alternated training methods to diversify instruction, strengthen learning opportunities and enhance program success.
- Encouraged class discussions by building discussions into lessons, actively soliciting input, asking open ended questions and using techniques to track student

### Deputy Training Manager (Wealth Management- Training) for ICICI bank

2017-01-2017-07

- IRDA, AMFI, NISM certified dedicated trainer for conducting financial product training in assessment centers.
- Coordinated with Senior Leadership and handled managerial needs by implementing fresh solutions into business strategies.
- Evaluated success of training programs and recommended improvements to upper management to enhance effectiveness.

### HR Team Leader at Kankei Relationship Marketing Services

2014-08 - 2016-03

Handling end to end HR Operations

### **HR Process Associate at Tata Consultancy Services**

2013-10 - 2014-05

Handling end to end HR Operations

### Fraud Risk Analyst JP Morgan Chase India Pvt. Ltd.

2009-06 - 2013- 07

 Collaborated on implementation of collection strategies with fraud and collections teams.

### **EDUCATION**

### L.L.B. (Mumbai University)

2018 - 2021

### M.H.R.D.M. (Mumbai University)- Masters in Human Resource Management and Development

2015-2018

### B.H.M.S. (Maharashtra University of Health Sciences)

2002 - 2008